Isabelle Hallin Papers MS219
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Isabelle Hallin Papers
1912 -- 2013
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Hallin, Isabelle
MS219
2.9 Linear Feet
5 Digital Object(s)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Biographical / Historical
Isabelle Louise Hallin was born in Saugus, Massachusetts on March 29, 1912 to Annie L. Hallin and Carl Fred Hallin. She graduated from Saugus High School in 1929 and went on to study at Jackson College, where she graduated in 1933.
Isabelle Hallin began teaching freshman and sophomore English at Saugus High School in November 1934. She organized a dramatic club at the school, directing and producing six three-act plays and several one-act plays in the three years she worked at the school.
In May 1937, Hallin invited students to her parents' house after school to practice for a performance of "Seventeen," because the school facility was too cold at the time. Shortly after this, rumors began to circulate in town that she had thrown a cocktail party for her underage students.
As the rumors spread, Minnie B. McDuffee of the Women's Christian Temperance Union decided to take action against the young teacher. She expressed her outrage at Hallin's alleged actions, and soon Saugus School Board member Maria Smith called for Hallin's resignation. Smith, along with two other members of the school board, Harry Wentworth and Waldo B. Russell, voted to not renew Hallin's contract with the school. Hallin hired an attorney named Daniel Canning to fight her dismissal. She also brought a case against Minnie B. McDuffee for slander.
News of Isabelle Hallin's situation and her campaign to get her job back made national headlines. Time Magazine ran an article titled "Storm in Saugus" on July 19, 1937. Articles about her also appeared in the Oakland Tribune, the New York Evening Post, the Boston Globe, True Story magazine, and a number of other papers throughout the country. Hallin also made several radio appearances to tell her side of the story.
In July 1937, the Saugus School Board voted 3-2 to deny Isabelle Hallin a public hearing to discuss her dismissal. George E. McCarrier and Paul A. Haley supported her reinstatement and were the dissenting votes in the losing battle for a public hearing. During the meeting, school board member Waldo B. Russell claimed that Hallin's dismissal was not motivated by the cocktail party rumors, but by poor performance and over-commitment to extracurricular activities, such as the dramatic productions. Maria Smith and Waldo B. Russell, two of the school board members who voted against a public hearing, required police escort to their homes after the meeting to avoid confronting approximately 500 angry protesters who had gathered outside.
In August 1937, Hallin moved to New York City to take the position of Junior Copywriter at Montgomery Ward, a department retailer. Following an illness, she came back to the greater Boston area in 1938, where she worked for the radio station WAAB of the Mutual Broadcasting System and the Salem Express. She relocated to New York again in October 1938, taking up seasonal employment at the jewelry retailer, Finlay Straus. In January 1939 she began working in advertising for the Eastern Isles Importing Company.
During this time period, Hallin began showing signs of depression and withdrew from family and friends. She rarely returned to Saugus due to the stress caused her by the rumors that had marred her name. Hallin was particularly upset by the effect these rumors had on her parents. A reporter named William Brawders, who visited Hallin in New York, wrote in a December 28, 1941 Salem Sunday Express article entitled "The Poor Girl Never Had a Chance," that during his visit he "learned that she condemned herself to exile for lifetime, to the hope she was giving happiness to her mother and dad."
On December 24, 1941 Isabelle Hallin turned on the gas stove, went to sleep, and died in her New York apartment in an apparent suicide. The cause of death was listed as "asphyxia by illuminating gas." Eleven days later, the Saugus School Committee unanimously voted to posthumously absolve Hallin of all charges against her name and character.
In March 2013, after a public campaign organized by Peter Manoogian, the town of Saugus dedicated a plaque to Isabelle Hallin in the Town Hall. The plaque reads, "May our actions within this Town Hall lead to greater wisdom and justice rather than sorrow and regret."
Custodial History
This collection was assembled by Peter Manoogian, who brought together Isabelle Hallin's papers inherited by her nephew Laurence Hallin and Mr. Manoogian's own additions purchased in online auctions.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains photographs, news clippings, correspondence, college class assignment papers, poetry, and a scrapbook from Isabelle Hallin's personal collection, inherited by her nephew Laurence Hallin. The collection also contains news clippings, photocopies of documents, photographs, and news items, interview transcripts, correspondence, and magazines compiled by Peter Manoogian during his research on Isabelle Hallin. Miss Hallin was fired from her teaching job at Saugus High School in 1937 after rumors circulated that she had provided alcohol to several students who had gone to her parents' home for theater practice one evening. The bulk of the material in the collection relates to Isabelle Hallin's efforts to retain her job and later to appeal her termination. This includes correspondence with relatives, friends, administrators, and supporters of her efforts to retain her position.
Also of interest are news clippings and photographs from theater productions that Hallin participated in or attended during high school, college, and afterwards. This includes programs from the Garrick Players, Pen Paint and Pretzels, and the Saugus High School Dramatic Society.
Teacher-student relationships; Teachers and community; Teachers -- Dismissal of -- United States; Alumni collections
- Isabelle Hallin papers, 1912 -- 2013; MS219.001; 2.9 Linear Feet; 5 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains photographs, news clippings, correspondence, college class assignment papers, poetry, and a scrapbook from Isabelle Hallin's personal collection, inherited by her nephew Laurence Hallin. The series also contains news clippings, photocopies of documents, photographs, and news items, interview transcripts, correspondence, and magazines compiled by Peter Manoogian during his research on Isabelle Hallin. Miss Hallin was fired from her teaching job at Saugus High School in 1937 after rumors circulated that she had provided alcohol to several students who had went to her parents' home for theater practice one evening. The bulk of the material in the series relates to Isabelle Hallin's efforts to retain her job and later to appeal her termination. This includes correspondence with relatives, friends, administrators, and supporters of her efforts to retain her position.
  Also of interest are news clippings and photographs from theater productions that Hallin participated in or attended during high school, college, and afterwards. This includes programs from the Garrick Players, Pen Paint and Pretzels, and the Saugus High School Dramatic Society.
  Arrangement
  This series is organized according to the original order assembled by collection donor, Peter Manoogian, with the exception of oversize items, which are arranged at the end of the series. The series is organized by subject and chronologically within each subject.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Front Matter, 2010 -- 2013; MS219.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 1 of 58)
  - Isabelle Louise Hallin birth certificate photocopy, 1912-03-29; MS219.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 2 of 58)
  - Isabelle Hallin baptism certificate, 1912-06-01; MS219.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 3 of 58)
  - Fred Hallin Letter to Nannie, 1920-09-06; MS219.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 4 of 58)
  - Isabelle Hallin, License to Have in Possession and Dispose of Wild Birds and Game Quadrupeds, 1934-05-09; MS219.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 5 of 58)
  - Letter to Isabelle Hallin, 1937-05-11; MS219.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 6 of 58)
  - Letter of Recommendation, Vernon W. Hayes, 1937-07-01; MS219.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 7 of 58)
  - Letter to Isabelle Hallin, 1937-07-07; MS219.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 8 of 58)
  - Postcard to Daniel Canning, 1937-07-12; MS219.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 9 of 58)
  - Article about Hallin Battle with School, photocopy, 1937-07-13; MS219.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 10 of 58)
  - Boston Post, "Teacher Loses Saugus Battle" article, photocopy, 1937-07-14; MS219.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 11 of 58)
  - The Boston Herald,"Miss Hallin loses Fight," article, photocopy, 1937-07-14; MS219.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 12 of 58)
  - Boston Daily Record, "Mob Fights to Uphold Teacher," article, photocopy, 1937-07-14; MS219.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 13 of 58)
  - Letter from Albion R. (Benny) Rice to Isabelle Hallin, 1937-07-14; MS219.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 14 of 58)
  - Boston Evening American, "School Head Absolves Teacher," article, photocopy, 1937-07-15; MS219.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 15 of 58)
  - Letter to Isabelle Hallin from W. R. Robinson, 1937-07-26; MS219.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 16 of 58)
  - Letter from Personal News Service, New York, 1937-07-28; MS219.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 17 of 58)
  - Letter from John T. Stuart to Edward Gibbs Jr., 1937-07-30; MS219.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 18 of 58)
  - Fired Teacher Defies Critics article, photocopy, 1937-07; MS219.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 19 of 58)
  - Postcard to Hallin from National Broadcasting Radio City, 1937-07-08; MS219.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 20 of 58)
  - Correspondence, 1937; MS219.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 21 of 58)
  - Correspondence about K.F.I., 1937; MS219.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 22 of 58)
  - Letter and Signed Photograph of Loretta Young, 1937; MS219.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 23 of 58)
  - Correspondence and Postcards, 1937; MS219.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 24 of 58)
  - Correspondence, 1937; MS219.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 25 of 58)
  - Oakland Tribune, 1937; MS219.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 26 of 58)
  - Goat Letter, 1937-10-21; MS219.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 27 of 58)
  - True Story Court of Human Relations, "Blonde Hussy or Gossip Martyr", 1937; MS219.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 28 of 58)
  - True Story Court of Human Relations, "Blonde Hussy or Gossip Martyr", 1937; MS219.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 29 of 58)
  - News Clipping, 1937; MS219.001.001.00030 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 30 of 58)
  - Isabelle Hallin Letter to Students of Saugus High School about a possible student strike, 1937; MS219.001.001.00031 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 31 of 58)
  - Telegrams, 1937; MS219.001.001.00032 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 32 of 58)
  - Saugus High School, School Investigating Committee, 1937 -- 1938; MS219.001.001.00033 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 33 of 58)
  - True Story Magazine, 1938; MS219.001.001.00034 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 34 of 58)
  - Isabel Hallin Record of Employment, 1939; MS219.001.001.00035 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 35 of 58)
  - Isabelle Hallin Death Certificate, 1941-12-26; MS219.001.001.00036 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 36 of 58)
  - Letters of Condolence to Isabelle Hallin's parents, 1941; MS219.001.001.00037 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 37 of 58)
  - Saugus Herald Article, "The Poor Little Girl Never Had a Chance", 1942-01-01; MS219.001.001.00038 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 38 of 58)
  - Letters of Condolence to Isabelle Hallin's Parents, 1942; MS219.001.001.00039 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 39 of 58)
  - Time Magazine, includes Hallin's obituary, 1942; MS219.001.001.00040 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 40 of 58)
  - Article, photocopy "Saugus Board Exonerates Late Teacher of Charges", 1942-01-06; MS219.001.001.00041 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 41 of 58)
  - Isabelle Hallin poetry, 1941; MS219.001.001.00042 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 42 of 58)
  - Scandal Mongers, 1942; MS219.001.001.00043 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 43 of 58)
  - Business Cards, 1937 -- 1941; MS219.001.001.00044 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 44 of 58)
  - Semper Fidelis, 1939; MS219.001.001.00045 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 45 of 58)
  - True Story: The Story of My Life by Isabelle Hallin, 1937 -- 1938; MS219.001.001.00046 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 46 of 58)
  - Correspondence, 1937; MS219.001.001.00047 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 47 of 58)
  - SUNY Albany Certificates for Teaching Services Bulletin, 1940; MS219.001.001.00048 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 48 of 58)
  - My Right to a Private Life by Isabelle Hallin, 1938 -- 1941; MS219.001.001.00049 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 49 of 58)
  - Bill Murphy Notes About Hallin family, 2012; MS219.001.001.00050 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 50 of 58)
  - Hallin Principle notes, 2012; MS219.001.001.00051 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 51 of 58)
  - Notes from Meeting at Saugus Library, 2012; MS219.001.001.00052 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 52 of 58)
  - Announcement, Biographical Presentation, True Sagus Story, 1930s "What Does Saugus Owe Ms Isabelle Hallin", 2012; MS219.001.001.00053 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 53 of 58)
  - Letter from NYPD Legal Bureau in Response to Peter Manoogian, 2012-12-07; MS219.001.001.00054 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 54 of 58)
  - Letter from NYPD Legal Bureau in Response to Peter Manoogian, 2013-01-08; MS219.001.001.00055 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 55 of 58)
  - Flyer, Unveiling Ceremony for the Plaque Created in honor of Isabelle Hallin, 2013; MS219.001.001.00056 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 56 of 58)
  - Letter from Bill Murphy to Peter Manoogian, 2013; MS219.001.001.00057 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 57 of 58)
  - Thank You Card from Larry Hallin to Peter Manoogian, 2013; MS219.001.001.00058 (Box 1)
    (Documents/News Clippings binder 58 of 58)
  - Isabelle Hallin Dedication video, 2013; MS219.001.001.00059 (Box 1)
    Video of Isabelle Hallin plaque dedication ceremony.
  - Isabelle Hallin drawing, 1932-01-25; MS219.001.001.00060 (Box 1)
  - Peter Manoogian notes, 2009 -- 2012; MS219.001.001.00061 (Box 1)
  - News Article, "Tavern Players' Season opened with Comedy Hit", 1933 -- 1941; MS219.001.001.00062 (Box 1)
  - Peter Manoogian Correspondence with Bill Murphy, 2012; MS219.001.001.00063 (Box 1)
  - Saugus Special Town Meeting Warrant, 2012; MS219.001.001.00064 (Box 1)
  - Photographs with Dalmation dog and post card, 1933 -- 1941; MS219.001.001.00065 (Box 1)
  - Isabelle Hallin promo photograph, 1933 -- 1941; MS219.001.001.00066 (Box 1)
  - Isabelle Hallin headshot photograph, 1933 -- 1941; MS219.001.001.00067 (Box 1)
  - Photograph of Isabelle Hallin, 1930; MS219.001.001.00068 (Box 1)
  - Photograph of Isabelle Hallin in group, theater production, 1933 -- 1941; MS219.001.001.00069 (Box 1)
  - Letter from NYPD Legal Bureau to Peter Manoogian, 2013-06-14; MS219.001.001.00070 (Box 1)
  - Hallin Plaque, 2013; MS219.001.001.00071 (Box 1)
  - Meeting with Author, 2012; MS219.001.001.00072 (Box 1)
  - Flyers for Isabelle Hallin Plaque Unveiling Ceremony, 2013; MS219.001.001.00073 (Box 1)
  - Note About Donation for Isabelle Hallin plaque, 2012-12-18; MS219.001.001.00074 (Box 1)
  - Saugus Advertiser, Vol. 125, No. 18 with "Article seeks 'Hallin Principle'", 2012; MS219.001.001.00075 (Box 1)
  - Saugus Advertiser, Vol. 125, No. 39 with "Hallin Plaque Unveiled", 2013; MS219.001.001.00076 (Box 1)
  - Isabelle Hallin Letter to her mother, 1927-06-24; MS219.001.001.00077 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 1 of 33)
  - Isabelle Hallin Tufts College, 1930-01-29; MS219.001.001.00078 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 2 of 33)
  - Isabelle Hallin Correspondence, 1930; MS219.001.001.00079 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 3 of 33)
  - The Golden Slippers, short story by Isabelle Hallin, 1931-01-08; MS219.001.001.00080 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 4 of 33)
  - Father's Family, short story by Isabelle Hallin, 1931-01-11; MS219.001.001.00081 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 5 of 33)
  - Isabelle Hallin Correspondence, 1931; MS219.001.001.00082 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 6 of 33)
  - A White Lie, short story by Isabelle Hallin, 1931-05-27; MS219.001.001.00083 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 7 of 33)
  - Tufts College Commencement program, 1931; MS219.001.001.00084 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 8 of 33)
  - Isabelle Hallin letter to her parents, 1931-06-17; MS219.001.001.00085 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 9 of 33)
  - Isabelle Hallin Tufts College Annual grade report, 1931-07; MS219.001.001.00086 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 10 of 33)
  - Fog, short story by Isabelle Hallin, 1931; MS219.001.001.00087 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 11 of 33)
  - Analysis of "The Black Monk" by Anton Chekhov, 1931; MS219.001.001.00088 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 12 of 33)
  - Death short story by Isabelle Hallin, 1931; MS219.001.001.00089 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 13 of 33)
  - The Universe About Us by Isabelle L. Hallin, thesis, 1932-01-25; MS219.001.001.00090 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 14 of 33)
  - On Victrolas essay by Isabelle Hallin, 1932-02-10; MS219.001.001.00091 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 15 of 33)
  - On What We Aren't essay by Isabelle Hallin, 1932-02-11; MS219.001.001.00092 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 16 of 33)
  - On Apologizing essay by Isabelle Hallin, 1932-02-15; MS219.001.001.00093 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 17 of 33)
  - Essay on "Sunset" and "Berets" by Isabelle Hallin, 1932-02-17; MS219.001.001.00094 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 18 of 33)
  - A Dark and Stormy Evening by Isabelle Hallin, 1932-02-18; MS219.001.001.00095 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 19 of 33)
  - Essay "On Noses" by Isabelle Hallin, 1932-02-24; MS219.001.001.00096 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 20 of 33)
  - On Horses by Isabelle Hallin, 1932-03-04; MS219.001.001.00097 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 21 of 33)
  - On Listening by Isabelle Hallin, 1932-03-09; MS219.001.001.00098 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 22 of 33)
  - I. L. Hallin Jackson College for Women fee bill, 1932-03-10; MS219.001.001.00099 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 23 of 33)
  - Stuck in the Mud by Isabelle Hallin, 1932-04-22; MS219.001.001.00100 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 24 of 33)
  - Essay on "Cats" by Isabelle Hallin, 1932-05-02; MS219.001.001.00101 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 25 of 33)
  - An Essay on Essays by Isabelle Hallin, 1932-05-13; MS219.001.001.00102 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 26 of 33)
  - Essay on "Wallpaper" by Isabelle Hallin, 1932-05-25; MS219.001.001.00103 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 27 of 33)
  - An Early Telephone Call essay by Isabelle Hallin, 1932-05-25; MS219.001.001.00104 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 28 of 33)
  - Seventy, Seventh Annual Commencement of Tufts College program, 1933-06-19; MS219.001.001.00105 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 29 of 33)
  - Pamela's Hank short story by Isabelle Hallin, 1930 -- 1933; MS219.001.001.00106 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 30 of 33)
  - Hallin handwritten copy of "Crossing the Bar" by Alfred Lord Tennyson, 1930 -- 1933; MS219.001.001.00107 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 31 of 33)
  - Analysis of "The Mill on the Floss" by George Elliott, 1930 -- 1933; MS219.001.001.00108 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 32 of 33)
  - Miscellaneous news clippings, 1930 -- 1933; MS219.001.001.00109 (Box 1)
    (College Days binder 33 of 33)
  - Front matter, photocopied articles, 1932; MS219.001.001.00110 (Box 1)
    (News Clippings binder 1 of 17)
  - Prettiest Girl at Tufts, 1933-06-17; MS219.001.001.00111 (Box 1)
    (News Clippings binder 2 of 17)
  - Lynn Telegram News "Appoint Two New Teachers in Saugus High", 1934-10-31; MS219.001.001.00112 (Box 1)
    (News Clippings binder 3 of 17)
  - Class of 1936 of Saugus High School Presents "Three Cornered Moon", 1936-02-15; MS219.001.001.00113 (Box 1)
    (News Clippings binder 4 of 17)
  - Various news clippings, 1937; MS219.001.001.00114 (Box 1)
    (News Clippings binder 5 of 17)
  - Various news clippings, 1938; MS219.001.001.00115 (Box 1)
    (News Clippings binder 6 of 17)
  - Various news clippings, 1939; MS219.001.001.00116 (Box 1)
    (News Clippings binder 7 of 17)
  - Miss Halm Superb in Play Last Night, 1940-08-06; MS219.001.001.00117 (Box 1)
    (News Clippings binder 8 of 17)
  - News clippings about Isabelle Hallin Funeral, 1941; MS219.001.001.00118 (Box 1)
    (News Clippings binder 9 of 17)
  - Massachusetts: Path of Glory, 1942-01-05; MS219.001.001.00119 (Box 1)
    (News Clippings binder 10 of 17)
  - Saugus Takes First Beating, 1937 -- 1940; MS219.001.001.00120 (Box 1)
    (News Clippings binder 11 of 17)
  - Various clippings, 1935 -- 1941; MS219.001.001.00121 (Box 1)
    (News Clippings binder 12 of 17)
  - Clippings, 1938; MS219.001.001.00122 (Box 1)
    (News Clippings binder 13 of 17)
  - Various clippings, 1941; MS219.001.001.00123 (Box 1)
    (News Clippings binder 14 of 17)
  - Various clippings, 1938; MS219.001.001.00124 (Box 1)
    (News Clippings binder 15 of 17)
  - Eminent Americans, 1937 -- 1941; MS219.001.001.00125 (Box 1)
    (News Clippings binder 16 of 17)
  - Various clippings, 1930 -- 1941; MS219.001.001.00126 (Box 1)
    (News Clippings binder 17 of 17)
  - Postcard to Isabelle Hallin, 1937-07-10; MS219.001.001.00127 (Box 1)
  - Snapshots empty photo album, Miami, Florida, 1938 -- 1939; MS219.001.001.00128 (Box 1)
  - Miss Hallin claims slander article, 1937 -- 1938; MS219.001.001.00129 (Box 1)
  - The Garrick Players programs, 1935; MS219.001.001.00130 (Box 1)
    (Drama and Theater binder 5 of 5)
  - The Garrick Players programs, 1935; MS219.001.001.00131 (Box 1)
  - Isabelle Hallin theater programs and clippings, 1936; MS219.001.001.00132 (Box 1)
  - Isabelle Hallin theater programs and clippings, 1937; MS219.001.001.00133 (Box 1)
  - Photographs from The Bishop Misbehaves, MS219.001.001.00134 (Box 1)
  - Peter Manoogian, Contributions List, 2012-12-21; MS219.001.001.00135 (Box 1)
  - Photographs of Isabelle Hallin and her father Fred Hallin, 1930; MS219.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
    (Pictures binder 1 of 49)
  - Photographs of Isabelle Hallin and unidentified persons, 1930 -- 1940; MS219.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
    (Pictures binder 2 of 49)
  - Isabelle Hallin baby photo, jailing photos, and group photograph, 1914 -- 1930; MS219.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
    (Pictures binder 3 of 49)